No welcome Ramsay and Brett to this idea
cafe where we are discussing what are
your thoughts and feelings on communism
or Marxism or both if you want to do
both so if anyone would like to start
there are three of us so I will be
participating and I can go first if no
one else wants to and I'll also be the
timekeeper awesome thank you thanks for
having us thank you
what a story Jubilee okay I will start
so this is what are my feelings and the
story I wrote notes on the Adina cafe
and rule Mego it not on this as I try to
just speak from the heart I think that
there is a lot of really amazing parts
to communism and Marxism I think that's
why in has stuck around is an ideology
that there is a lot of things that are
beautiful about coming together and
working as a group for the benefit of
the group I also think when it's been
implemented in the actual real world our
human there's been some some there's
been huge downfalls there has been mass
murder and there's a lot of repression
that happens when you want a group of
people to do a thing especially when
you're not acknowledging that that group
of people it's made up of individuals
and have their own autonomous beliefs
and when you have a central authority
that is theoretically supposed to at one
point give up power but I think human
nature is when you have power you want
to hold on to it I think the words
communism and Marxism both get
interchanged even in my mind for sure
and that there's a lot I mean I live in
an I think a fairly socialist country
Canada and I think it has a lot of
benefit because of the socialism part of
it I love having universal health care
I like I've experienced universal
healthcare and didn't have to you know
declare bankruptcy because of having
brain surgery twice and radiation and I
think that throwing the baby out with
the bathwater saying that like we don't
have with there's nothing they miss
value in communism and Marxism is as bad
as saying there is whatever the opposite
of that is that we have to follow at the
letter to the law right like it has to
be followed
as it is as it was set out by Karl Marx
um I think that for a lot of things not
just a Marxism we tend to hold the
person who came up with it as gospel
instead of honoring that they weren't in
this time period they do it with Darwin
and the theory of evolution and
definitely with with Karl Marx and
communism of like well this is how it
has to be and then both they're
simultaneously this is with it's never
been implemented and we need to
implement it exactly and none of those
people knew what we know now I mean
Darwin didn't know genetics which is a
huge part of you know evolution and Karl
Marx didn't know well this entire
century didn't know what happened during
World War Two didn't know what the
Internet technology the the global world
that we now live in I think there's a
lot of a benefit to finding what works
in all of the things we have done in the
past and honor that we have to move
forward with nothing we've done in the
past meeting there has to be a new way a
new way that isn't moving backwards and
is moving forwards and I think whatever
that way is has to honor our individual
autonomy that we all have our own
decisions around our own space in
society which capitalism pretends to do
and I don't think does a great job of
because it's participate or starve
communism definitely doesn't do a good
job of and under where it's been
implemented or its kind of assigns you
what you're supposed to be and at the
same time we have to honor our group
involvement how to have our autonomous
groups that hopefully are our choice to
be part of and that there's a space for
everyone and so what I'm trying to
create in the world is very much I
believe a mixture of the best parts of
what we have had in the past went from
tribalism all the way through to
capitalism including absolutism and so
I'm going to stop there and I forgot to
mute everyone else who I was talking
because I do what Brett was doing
that's about what I'm talking about like
yeah of course but it says ramune it so
it's not because of the technology it's
like yeah yeah yeah technology
and so uh anyone to go first next who
will go next you know I would like to
add an input maybe well you can go if
you would like to go sure I'll go I'll
just say that I think I agree with 100
percent of your signal or 99 percent of
your signal and it's very reasonable and
I would I would add that I would
stipulate that Marx didn't know very
much about the the new dogma of
scientism he although he was a
materialist he was more of a in terms of
Ken Wilber he was a lower right
reductionist so he didn't understand the
full complexity of reality so but we
have to we have to understand this
within a broader context of you know
mind body culture and society and and
and in the bigger picture
I think Marx is my new secure tool but
his philosophy is what remains with us
to this day and so we have to deal with
the kind of philosophical remnants of
what you either call neo Marxism or some
other field of speculative inquiry so
but but the point is that the point is
that Marx is not just some person we can
cast aside in the name of some kind of
libertarian ideology
although libertarianism is needed to be
included within this new social
theoretical metamodel but that's my
starting point but how we can include
diverse perspectives within our you know
trans libertarianism and transhumanism
along with trans Marxism and combine
these all together into kind of a
unified identity that's diverse and
unique and proliferate as
multi-dimensional as it is coherent and
that's kind of my idea for a system that
we can use so if that makes sense to
anybody I hope that makes sense
just kind of an inroad into where we can
go with this into the future hopefully
to to go in any direction we choose so
thank you all right thank you Brett from
Z would you like to share sure I didn't
prepare any five-minute speech on this I
just wanted to enter into the room you
know just to have a general conversation
about the topic for sure um I kind of
view I'm thinking that Marxism in
communism is kind of the path that we
are on with game B I think the idea of
socialism in the late 19th century early
20th century was very much
you know the idea of socialism very much
similar to the game B group that we have
today we're more or less continuing on
the same path that those guys began and
with new or better information obviously
but I feel like you know what's weird is
in the last 50 years that there has been
almost no development or conversation in
this realm because it was assumed or at
least portrayed as if guys you know
there's no other better system
capitalism is the best we're ever gonna
do so let's just try to make it work and
do whatever we can and so I feel like
there's we've lost a massive opportunity
to to make things better than the last
50 years because we ignored you know all
of that and we and and I think society
began to just produce too much and go
down this capitalist path where where
where we're at now but so in implement I
mean I guess I would say that Marxism is
is essentially more theory theory and
philosophy than actual implementation
and the idea that you know the mode of
production the material the mode of
production and the socio-economic system
you know it kind of relates to how the
materialist old functions in and how
societies function is is excellent is a
good you know reality but you know
obviously the socio-economic system that
we have dictates and the governance
structure dictates the outcome
and so the you know the Communists in
that you know in a hundred years ago
when the Russia tried to do it
they had different challenges that we
have today didn't have computers they
didn't have the advancements of modes of
production that we have today so they
couldn't implement it in in a manner in
which it could have been implemented to
say today so they're not all hundred
percent wrong but they still I feel like
they're still missing something like
they're what's more interesting for me
is to look at how they're the same
like what did Russia do what did all of
these so-called communist countries have
the same rather than different and the
thing that was the same is the money the
money itself was physical property and
so you you you controlled the mode of
production you know the resources land
the labor and you comment and you made
that the communal ownership but what
about the money the money itself became
a physical property which is in relation
to the physical world to the you know
the outcome with the production so I
think that's really the key um and that
piece is something that has never been
tried and that piece is something that
was never possible until today because a
currency if you know the purpose of a
currency is to have a unit of exchange
to be able to exchange stuff you know
and use pricing system to be able to do
that and so you had to have something
that was physical because I didn't trust
you if I went out on my community and I
traded with people I didn't trust I had
to trust the currency and so that's why
we ended up you know coming to gold
because gold had those features of of
trust you know of weight of carats etc
that we knew that I didn't trust Jubilee
to honor her commitments but I knew the
valid the value of the gold so you know
anyway so here we are today
but we're still using this currency as
if it's a physical piece of property but
we're allowing these banks to create
this currency this physical piece of
property that relates to the real
material physical world you know in a
centralized way anyway so one of the
things I'd like to do in this discussion
though is I
to kind of get away from this language
of communism Marxism and and more or
less talk about the actual pieces like
for example you have land you've got
production you've got labor you've got a
currency and so the more appropriate
language is that if we can take this
puzzle all these different pieces and
rearrange them and see what manner of
outcome we can get and so that's the
that's I think the fundamental area on
which we need to focus and then we're
focusing on the game the game be crowd
right so if we get too caught up in the
past with these labels and fighting with
one another we're not going to move
forward so you know some of these
physical things exist you have land
you've got resources you have
distribution you've got transportation
you have labor so all those pieces exist
and then the pieces that are that that
we created the currency can be is it
time okay well really quickly the that
last piece the currency piece has always
been the one piece that we haven't that
we just assumed was natural and must be
that way but that's not true
the currency currency you're not a
current to see the current the horizon
of time the career I would add to that
maybe I can add something
yeah it's now open so for the next 15
minutes up to 30 minutes we can go keep
it a rind rule Omega
yeah so omega kind of using a system of
just kind of honing the collective
intelligence
I believe Marx Marx is a collective node
within a greater collective multiplex if
you will if I can call it a multiplex a
diverse multiplex of historical
constellations including Jordan Peterson
who in some respects he is a Marxist
because he believes in that determine
the determinant philosophy of the south
so in fact Jordan Peterson is Ammar
in the sense that Hegel received his
lineage from the same exact you know he
inherited the same exact field of
knowledge are the Epis tema
that Michele calls the Epis tema of
scientific knowledge that that was
generated through Marx that was
generated through the present day that
we we used to call the determinate
object or the determine itself and this
is what is the determine itself has been
has been lost throughout the historical
process and so we're trying to recover
Hegel's determine itself whether we're
Peterson or kin Wilbur or or some other
philosopher but although Martin Luther
King didn't really appreciate this
concept of concentrating all one's power
into oneself as opposed to the multiplex
however so if that makes sense so I yeah
that's kind of how I was I would like to
stipulate that in a sense Peterson is a
Marxist because he believes in the
Hegelian
know the idea of the Hegelian gnosis
which is the the immaterial object of
the purely transcendent dialectic
anderson considered himself a marxist i
don't he doesn't consider himself a
Marxist that is he uh not categorically
but historically and a historic he does
okay I'm not I don't watch a lot of
Jordan Peterson he doesn't really speak
to me um but I like what Renzi had
suggested if Brett is open to it of
talking about what pieces of under
Marxism even if I'm not super familiar
with Marxism as its own like I know
history I've studied Cambodia I've
studied China and Russia as far as it as
communism being implemented and I
believe in a lot of the fundamental
pieces of like personal autonomy and
sovereignty and how we bring that into
working in my best interest also works
in the group's best interest and pieces
like the money piece eyes I know with
common planet which is frenzies project
that is the central piece right is that
we
we we don't get rid of money the
currency has changed its changed into a
different completely different incentive
incentive structure okay right that's a
good transition there because what I
wanted to go into when I was saying that
we should look at the pieces but more
than that in this particular
conversation in Marxism and communism
and and all these other isms were what
we're altom utley talking about is okay
so what is the game and what do what
kind of game do we want for ourselves
personally and then for our community
and then obviously the global sphere so
when you look at the the game the rules
that are in place now so it's better to
say don't call this capitalist I mean
it's good to have definitions obviously
but the problem with labeling this
system capitalism is is that you can't
okay America is not the same as say UK
or France or Japan or yes a lot of the
same pieces are used similarly but
there's different variations that within
within that so ultimately what I'd like
to look at is you know what are the
things that we can all agree on like
what are the what should the game be
producing right and then take those
pieces and reformulate them so that it
produces those things that we want and
the outcome that we want so that's what
I mean this is suggest so you know the
this is the thing that most capitalists
and other people don't do today they
don't ask themselves you know you know
they don't look at what the game is
actually doing you know does the game
give individual sovereignty the answer
is no most you're either you're a master
or you're a slave essentially if you
know either you have the means and your
money is making money and you don't have
to worry about making money or you do
and so that's a so you know person at
least in this particular instance is
sovereign and then the other question is
should there be other players in this
game that are non-human corporations
governments and should they have the
same rights and to access to land and
property as humans so like who's who's
who's a player basically who are the
players of the game and what are the
rules and what power do those
individuals players
and so and you look at the capitalism or
communism or any ism or whatever system
you have if you look at it from that
lens and you answer those questions you
get different you know answers then if
you were to judge the ISM yeah you know
yesterday if I were to ask younger
people who-who have a negative
impression of companies we don't know
what it is you know assume that it's
totalitarianism or you know centralize
power and killing people etc no one's
gonna want that of course but that's why
it's better to move away from the labels
and look at the actual what the actual
this game is mm-hmm I agree I think that
the pieces I think the pieces of motors
pertains to me and us co-creating game B
together is can we co-create game B
together
meaning I like the piece of saying my
individual sovereignty here's what I
want I like the piece of coming together
and creating games and creating the idea
of what the global system would look
like but if we a thousand 10,000 people
or worse 10 people come together and
create this idea and work forward to
implement it without it being without us
keeping in mind the next person and the
next person and the next person to come
on board are we recreating the what was
done in in every communist country and I
think done poorly and we couldn't do it
until now which is the concentrated
power right like well this is our rules
and we made them and now you have to if
you come on board you have to live by
them without them having any group or
individual sovereignty to help change
those rules and help them evolve and
help them improve I would agree with
that assessment
and I I might add that that it's more
it's that that's accurate and that that
seems to be very accurate but for the
sake of depth and deeper honing or going
into that I would add to this that the
fact that I think Marxism is is not it
has to be dissolved into its it you you
know we can't keep this game
Marxism is game a clearly but meta
Marxism is not game a necessarily if you
read Brent Cooper's abstract philosophy
there is there which I just friended him
but uh so I mean there's there's
different aspects of marks that have to
be embedded within a historical
understanding Andrea procreated as a
meta system you know a meta ontology and
meta at the stem ology before we can
really approach it in a coherent fashion
and before we react to something that is
not actually the depth of you know we're
just finding ghosts or we're just having
a game of hide-n-seek with marks but so
I would add so I would say I would say
we have to we have to include the
aspects of marks that were determinate
and that were satisfactory for the
conditions that they cost such as French
Revolution in night 18 70 and so forth
and so on
so I feel that but but Marxism you know
capitalism is game a - but the thing is
capitalism is the same game that
produced it basically what I would like
to point out here is the postmodern
perspective which says that Marxism
Marxism is a totalitarian belief system
according to post-modernism this is this
is the core this is the core moment of
understanding I think we have to
understand
according to Michel Foucault
post-modernism well first of all he
didn't recognize a category of
post-modernism
he was a historical archaeologist as
such he analyzed Marxism and he
understood that Marxism is really a
failed totalitarian system he himself
understood that Marxism is a
totalitarian system and so I think most
of the post modernists understood that
Marxism at what what parts of Marxism as
you understand it would you like to see
implemented in game be what words do you
think are or wouldn't like what are the
Penguins oh yeah right the idea of alien
nation of the worker from his work the
things that matter in a capitalist
society but yeah I mean things that
truly matter to to to building and and
helping us thrive as a modern industrial
and patriotic nation or urination Canada
so I'm worth excuse me
so I'm more politically I feel right
then left but however I would say that
Marx is somebody that has to be
understood and negated and transcended
but we can't negate something without
comprehending the essence or the core
the Dean of the Dingaan Zeke not the
Dean for Zeke which we have in our mind
of the object which contaminates us you
know okay so that's what I would say
about Marx if we're looking at the the
the past systems and and we're looking
at the present system you know most
people today don't even know what the
game is right now if you asked you know
is the game fair you know what is the
game today who are the players the
players are individual people
corporations and governments right but
if you think about what the game is the
game is to amass capital which is
selfish property that you then use to
acquire other property but you enter
into this game when you're born with the
same number of points let's just say
assume that you know the money in this
case is points and you need this money
obviously in order to act it to have the
means of life to access the water or the
land and the materials right this is a
fact of life today and so if we're
playing is gaining today and and in your
what are the rules well your parents and
the people who played the game before
you you get to inherit their points in
the game and so that you know ask the
question well is that necessary or fair
you know being such that this game that
we're playing this physical money is not
just physical property but it's it turns
into power because it's the tool the
unit of exchange that we use access the
real goods so it's not just
the physical properties more than that's
a super tool and so then you look at the
characteristics okay so how can we
compete in this game you know what's my
role in this game I have to amass this
money and the only way I can get money
as an individual is if I agree
voluntarily to submit and work doing
something presumably that I have a
choice but not really because I have
limited choice based on my community and
my experiences etc so though when you
when you attack the the game the
system's based on simple terminology and
like what are the rules what are the
game how do you play and is that fair
and you'll realize no it's not because
we imagine playing the game of Monopoly
and you get to start with nothing but
then your opponents get to start with
what their parents and generations of
relatives were able to amass oh you know
throughout that that's not a fair game
you know the time frame is different the
amount of money is different and then up
not naturally the game itself is broken
because the money itself this property
could instantly lose value if another
group like the United States and you
happen to be in a different country
devalue your currency and so the whole
system that we have today is so complex
and all of it is a system of basically
power who owns the land the production
of labor is essentially only a few
people and clearly that's not the game
that anybody wants to play I certainly
don't want to play that game
so that's game a you know when what is
the game the game is to amass as much
property and it can extract the value
using this currency and that's it and
and and it's a terrible game so the
whatever language that we use for the
new game has to be something as simple
for people to understand what their role
is and they have to actually be excited
to play that game
whereas today I don't know about you
guys but this is why we have epidemics
of opioid overdoses and suicides because
nobody wants to play this game
anymore
you know I don't see the future for
myself in this game I don't want to to
labor doing jobs that probably
shouldn't even exist if for the most
part just for the sake of proving that I
deserve to live that's insane
I'm
human being of course I deserve to live
of course I deserved that access to the
things in the world so tell me how I
should I want to get access to these
things differently than today and
unfortunately there isn't a story for
that right now you know but this is you
know back to kind of my comic plant idea
is is that you would get a currency you
could never run out as a human being you
know why should you not have access to
the goods that we produce from the
Commons doesn't make any sense
of course you should the question of
course is should you have unlimited
access you know no because that would be
unreasonable and not realistic but
should you have unfettered open access
to compete for the limited resources yes
do you have that today no and so about
common planet that so the idea of
creating a new game is awesome I love
the idea of create a new game any day
really cuz I really don't like the one
we're playing the issue with the one
we're playing is it's complex and you
don't have a choice in playing it mm-hmm
I love your idea of common planet I
would sign up for it tomorrow
but like all games there's no end point
and you don't really get to choose
whether or not you play what is in place
for the negative implications that
happen and how people can feed that back
into the system so it continually
improved like it for some reason it's
catastrophic I don't know why but a
catastrophic that you give everyone
money based on the fact that they go to
school and just live their life and and
there's a some outcome we didn't foresee
how do people the players in the game
improve the game so they can fix that
piece so they can still keep playing or
start with a whole new game right
because that's monopoly as long as it is
you get to restart it throughout history
there's been periodic Jubilees because
of inequities in in accumulation of
capital and resources so anytime that
happens just like in the game of
Monopoly you restart you know you can't
continue playing the game if people
don't have any money to play so you have
to restart and give them a new money
anyway but this is different though
Jubilee in what you're suggesting is
that yeah
giving people currency but that doesn't
necessarily change the physical right
just because I give you this money I say
Jubilee you have access to you know this
currency is equal to say you know ten
thousand laptops it doesn't mean that
Jubilee is just gonna sit at home and
you know take classes and do nothing I
mean she might by the way but the whole
purpose of this new game I might be
taking classes doing nothing that would
be fine so people will do that but my
point is is though that the game would
be that you know we're all of the
information of what your community is
producing is available to everybody
you'll be able to see you know
everything is happening in community so
as things are being recorded and
measured and and and you can see where
you're going and you can see you can set
metrics on what you're gonna do in the
future
what you know and and what and what
actually happens so you can change
people's in your community people will
change their behavior based on what the
needs and desires of the community are
and if you don't want to participate
no one's gonna force you but certainly
then your community would wouldn't have
the the the prosperity and I don't mean
prosperity in the physical sense but
prosperity you know socially
structurally that that you could
otherwise happen so then you might have
to work more but those would all be
options that the people would make
themselves so it wouldn't be you know it
wouldn't be force but it doesn't it
doesn't mean that society would collapse
and that's more it's just like we can
invent a new game but we also have to
include that whatever we invent could
also go wrong and so we have to put
things in place along there okay I might
like it it's possible that the community
doesn't you know grow enough food or
produce enough resources for that
particular year but you would you would
know that that's happening because all
of the instruments you're recording
everything you're recording the
production the consumption so it's not
like you were going to be surprised oh
we didn't grow enough we didn't plant
enough Apple its reason you would know I
have a question for that to respond to
that how would how would this
Society of structural integrity cultural
integrity how could such a society
maintain itself over the generate over a
generation like let's say within a
generation without deteriorating under
our current economic conditions which
are post capitalists so we we have to we
have to recognize that we have a
different set of norms than than any
structural or cultural libertarianism
fascism or communism so we can't just go
back to the fascism of the past but I
feel we we have to proceed with a new a
new kind of utopianism of the heart or
if you will of the heart but of a higher
order of intelligence which extrapolates
the heart the heart neuro neuronal
network towards the mind and the brain
so that way you have an inter connecting
unity between both fields of you know a
kind of a kind of intelligence network
that's like a my Seeley ated network
between heart and head in order to
circulate you know Marxism can be the
feet
Jordan Peterson can be the heart and
then you know 'shmock timber and these
Buckminster Fuller can be the head you
know it's like different I want to be my
own heart and head but I'm sore at the
30 minute mark
I would like to give everyone
opportunity to like wrap up their what
they want to say in like one minute if
you could including part of that if you
feel called how this process was for you
what you got from this process that
would be awesome if not just wrap it up
on communism and Marxism
or whatever you want to say in your
minute so whoever wants to go first
thank you yeah rimsky or okay sorry
somebody else go we won't you start all
right I usually end it but that is that
is fine I will what I don't know what to
say now
usually usually Angela by my endpoint is
just that I think we need to have a
feedback system whatever we create
to start from where we are and it has to
be something that honors that there will
be little pieces that break even if the
whole thing doesn't break and I think it
runs you answered what that is that
there's data feeding back into it and
and looking at how we get there and that
it always includes the next people how
do we include the new they don't even if
there's a thousand of us that co-create
something together
what is the thousands and one person
coming on board look like what is the
ten thousand and so that is that is my
final yeah I would I would agree I was I
would say ha what does that thousand
thousand thousand person look like and
then how how does that person how can I
guess how can we increase
I think it's been called the Dunbar
number so you can have a greater
holistic on you know onboarding or you
know so that way you're not just
spitting in time onboarding you're
spinning you're time increasing the
magnitude and the amplification of
resonances as an as you continue to ramp
up the the spiraling you know energetics
so to speak of the process and this will
may we can have we can we can have any
system we don't fill in the blank with
any system as a you know or any
dialectic but it could be it could be
blockchain or anything but I feel that
distributed collective intelligence can
come from the left or the right and we
don't want to exclude either one of
those distributed forms of collective
intelligence that's my final cases I
agree one percent with what you just
said there the when the you know the
communists they collectivized all of the
means of production they obviously they
gathered all the information they knew
what they were producing how much food
etc but see all that data ended up going
to individuals in a centralized manner
and so in only a select few individuals
had all the information and had to make
decision so power became centralized so
today using computers we can
decentralize that process and change
that dynamic now but one of the other
problems of okay so you've got
the governance structure there right we
know that it's best that allow each
individual person their voice and vote
is better than centralizing power in one
person because that like jublee said at
the beginning you know concentration of
power always corrupts so the other
problem though is is that even
decentralized power in decision-making
in governance structures within a game
where the resources are centralized like
capitalism and the game is for
extraction
it means that you're still going to have
concentrations of power because the
thing that you're trying to make
governance decisions about is the thing
that already exists and is held by only
a few people so the solution is to make
sure that the the game is not extraction
and and collection of property as power
but rather the acquisition of property
for use and need for human life rather
than for control and and and extraction
through the Commons which is capitalism
so once you've changed the property
portion of the game then finally direct
democracy actually is the best
governance structure because then the
thing that we're we're voting on isn't
who gets more land and who gets more
power but what should we build in our
community and how we should build it
that's a different conversation then who
should who's going to benefit and who's
to are going to take money from and who
we gonna tax and who we gonna know it's
nonsense game right now I think I would
learn Randy the conversation otherwise
I'm sure we game be people could go on
about this for weeks and weeks so we'll
say goodbye to the potential YouTube
audience and then go on like a